In the last video, we talked
在过去的视频中 我们谈到
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
about the hypothesis representation for logistic progression.
逻辑回归中假设函数的表示方法
What I'd like to do now is
现在 我想
tell you about something called the
告诉大家一个叫做
decision boundary, and this
决策边界(decision boundary)的概念
will give us a better sense
这个概念能更好地帮助我们
of what the logistic regression
理解逻辑回归的
hypothesis function is computing.
假设函数在计算什么
To recap, this is
让我们回忆一下
what we wrote out last time,
这是我们上次写下的公式
where we said that the
当时我们说
hypothesis is represented as
假设函数可以表示为
H of X equals G of
h(x)=g(θTx)
theta transpose X, where G
其中函数g
is this function called the
被称为S形函数（sigmoid function）
sigmoid function, which looks like this.
看起来是应该是这样的形状
So, it slowly increases from zero
它从零开始慢慢增加至1
to one, asymptoting at one.
逐渐逼近1
What I want to do now is
现在让我们
try to understand better when
更进一步来理解
this hypothesis will make
这个假设函数何时
predictions that Y is
会将y预测为1
equal to one versus when it
什么时候又会将
might make predictions that Y
y预测为0
is equal to zero and understand
让我们更好的理解
better what the hypothesis function
假设函数的应该是怎样的
looks like, particularly when we have more than one feature.
特别是当我们的数据有多个特征时
Concretely, this hypothesis is
具体地说 这个假设函数
out putting estimates of the
输出的是
probability that Y is
给定x时
equal to one given X is prime.
y=1的概率
So if we wanted to
因此 如果我们想
predict is Y equal to
预测y=1
one or is Y equal
还是等于0
to zero here's something we might do.
我们可以这样做
When ever the hypothesis its that
只要该假设函数
the problem with y being one
输出y=1的概率
is greater than or equal
大于或等于0.5
to 0.5 so this means
那么这表示
that it is more likely to
y更有可能
be y equals one than y
等于1而不是0
equals zero then let's predict Y equals one.
因此 我们预测y=1
And otherwise, if the probability
在另一种情况下 如果
of, the estimated probability of
预测y=1
Y being one is less
的概率
than 0.5, then let's predict Y equals zero.
小于0.5 那么我们应该预测y=0
And I chose a greater
在这里 我选择大于等于
than or equal to here and less than here.
在这里我选择小于
If H of X is equal
如果h(x)的值
to 0.5 exactly, then
正好等于0.5 那么
we could predict positive or
我们可以预测为1
negative vector but a put a
也可以预测为0
great deal on to here
但是这里我选择了大于等于
so we default maybe to predicting
因此我们默认
a positive if your
如果h(x)等于0.5的话
vector is 0.5 but that's
预测选择为1
a detail that really doesn't matter that much.
这只是一个细节 不用太在意
What I want to do is understand
下面 我希望大家能够
better when it is
清晰地理解
exactly that H of
什么时候h(x)
X will be greater or equal
将大于或等于
to 0.5, so that
0.5 从而
we end up predicting Y is equal to one.
我们最终预测y=1
If we look at this plot
如果我们看看
of the sigmoid function, we'll notice
S形函数的曲线图 我们会注意到
that the sigmoid function, G
S函数
of Z, is greater than
只要z大于
or equal to 0.5
或等于0时
whenever Z is
g(z)就将大于
greater than or equal to zero.
或等于0.5
So is in this half of
因此 在曲线图的这半边
the figure that, G takes
g的取值
on values that are 0.5 and higher.
大于或等于0.5
This is not clear, that's the 0.5.
因为这个交点就是0.5
So when Z is
因此 当z大于0时
positive, G of Z,
g(z) 也就是这个
the sigmoid function, is greater than or equal to 0.5.
S形函数 是大于或等于0.5的
Since the hypothesis for
由于逻辑回归的
logistic regression is H of
假设函数h(x)
X equals G of theta
等于g(θTx)
transpose X. This is
因此
therefore going to be greater
函数值将会
than or equal to 0.5
大于或等于0.5
whenever theta transpose
只要θ转置乘以x
X is greater than or equal to zero.
大于或等于0
So what was shown, right,
因此 我们看到
because here theta transpose X
因为这里θ转置x
takes the row of Z.
取代了z的位置
So what we're shown is that
所以我们看到
our hypothesis is going
我们的假设函数
to predict Y equals one
将会预测y=1
whenever theta transpose X
只要θ转置乘以x
is greater than or equal to 0.
大于或等于0
Let's now consider the other
现在让我们来考虑
case of when a hypothesis
假设函数
will predict Y is equal to 0.
预测y=0的情况
Well, by similar argument, H
类似的
of X is going to be
h(θ)将会
less than 0.5 whenever G
小于0.5 只要
of Z is less than
g(z)小于0.5
0.5 because the range
这是因为
of values of Z that
z的定义域上
calls Z to take on
导致g(z)取值
values less that 0.5, well that's when Z is negative.
小于0.5的部分 是z小于0的部分
So when G of Z is less than 0.5.
所以当g(z)小于0.5时
Our hypothesis will predict
我们的假设函数将会预测
that Y is equal to zero, and
y=0
by similar argument to what
根据与之前
we had earlier, H of
类似的原因
X is equal G of
h(x)等于
theta transpose X. And
g(θTx)
so, we'll predict Y equals
因此 只要
zero whenever this quantity
θ转置乘以x小于0
theta transpose X is less than zero.
我们就预测y等于0
To summarize what we just
总结一下我们刚才所讲的
worked out, we saw that if
我们看到
we decide to predict whether
如果我们要决定
Y is equal to one or
预测y=1
Y is equal to zero,
还是y=0
depending on whether the estimated
取决于
probability is greater than
y=1的概率
or equal 0.5, or whether
大于或等于0.5
it's less than 0.5, then
还是小于0.5
that's the same as saying that
这其实就等于说
will predict Y equals 1
我们将预测y=1
whenever theta transpose axis greater
只需要θ转置乘以x
than or equal to 0,
大于或等于0
and we will predict Y is
另一方面我们将预测y=0
equal to zero whenever theta transpose X
只需要θ转置乘以x
is less than zero.
小于0
Let's use this to better
通过这些 我们能更好地
understand how the hypothesis
理解如何利用逻辑回归的假设函数
of logistic regression makes those predictions.
来进行预测
Now, let's suppose we have
现在假设我们有
a training set like that shown
一个训练集
on the slide, and suppose
就像幻灯片上的这个
our hypothesis is H of
接下来我们假设我们的假设函数是
X equals G of theta
h(x)等于g()
zero, plus theta one X1
括号里面是θ0加上θ1x1
plus theta two X2.
加上θ2乘以x2
We haven't talked yet about how
目前我们还没有谈到
to fit the parameters of this model.
如何拟合此模型中的参数
We'll talk about that in the next video.
我们将在下一个视频中讨论这个问题
But suppose that variable procedure
但是假设我们
to be specified, we end
已经拟合好了参数
up choosing the following values for the parameters.
我们最终选择了如下值
Let's say we choose theta zero
比方说 我们选择θ0
equals three, theta one
等于-3 θ1
equals one, theta two equals one.
等于1 θ2等于1
So this means that my parameter
因此 这意味着我的
vector is going to be
参数向量将是
theta equals minus 311.
θ等于[-3 1 1]
So, we're given this
这样 我们有了
choice of my hypothesis parameters,
这样的一个参数选择
let's try to figure out where
让我们试着找出
a hypothesis will end up
假设函数何时将
predicting y equals 1 and where it
预测y等于1
will end up predicting y equals 0.
何时又将预测y等于0
Using the formulas that we
使用我们在
worked on the previous slide, we know
在上一张幻灯片上展示的公式 我们知道
that Y equals 1 is
y更有可能是1
more likely, that is the
或者说
probability that Y equals
y等于1的概率
1 is greater than 0.5
大于0.5
or greater than or equal to 0.5.
或者大于等于0.5
Whenever theta transpose x
只要θ转置x
is greater than zero.
大于0
And this formula that I
我刚刚加了下划线的
just underlined minus three
这个公式
plus X1 plus X2 is,
-3加上x1再加上x2
of course, theta transpose
当然就是θ转置x
X when theta is equal
这是当θ等于
to this value of the parameters
我们选择的这个参数值时
that we just chose.
θ转置乘以x的表达
So, for any example, for
因此 举例来说
any example with features X1
对于任何样本
and X2 that satisfy this
只要x1和x2满足
equation that minus 3
这个等式 也就是-3
plus X1 plus X2
加上x1再加x2
is greater than or equal to 0.
大于等于0
Our hypothesis will think
我们的假设函数就会认为
that Y equals 1 is
y等于1
more likely, or will predict that Y is equal to one.
的可能性较大 或者说将预测y=1
We can also take minus three
我们也可以
and bring this to the right
将-3放到不等式右边
and rewrite this as X1
并改写为x1
plus X2 is greater than or equal to three.
加号x2大于等于3
And so, equivalently, we found
这样是等价的 我们发现
that this hypothesis will predict
这一假设函数将预测
Y equals one whenever X1
y=1 只要
plus X2 is greater than or equal to three.
x1+x2大于等于3
Let's see what that means on the figure.
让我们来看看这在图上是什么意思
If I write down the equation,
如果我写下等式
X1 plus X2 equals three,
x1+x2等于3
this defines the equation of a straight line.
这将定义一条直线
And if I draw what that straight
如果我画出这条直线
line looks like, it gives
它将表示为
me the following line which passes
这样一条线 它通过
through 3 and 3 on
通过x1轴上的3
the X1 and the X2 axis.
和x2轴上的3
So the part of the input space,
因此 这部分的输入样本空间
the part of the
这一部分的
X1, X2 plane that corresponds
X1-X2平面
to when X1 plus X2 is greater than or equal to three.
对应x1加x2大于等于3
That's going to be this very top plane.
这将是上面这个半平面
That is everything to the
也就是所有
up, and everything to the upper
上方和所有右侧的部分
right portion of this magenta line that I just drew.
相对我画的这条洋红色线来说
And so, the region where our
所以
hypothesis will predict Y
我们的假设函数预测
equals 1 is this
y等于1的区域
region, you know, is
就是这片区域
really this huge region, this
是这个巨大的区域
half-space over to the upper right.
是右上方的这个半平面
And let me just write that down.
让我把它写下来
I'm gonna call this the Y
我将称它为
equals one region, and in
y=1区域
contrast the region where
与此相对
X1 plus X2 is
x1加x2
less than three, that's when
小于3的区域
we will predict that Y,
也就是我们预测
Y is equal to zero, and
y等于0的区域
that corresponds to this region.
是这一片区域
You know, itt's really a half-plane, but
你看到 这也是一个半平面
that region on the left is
左侧的这个半平面
the region where our hypothesis predict Y equals 0.
是我们的假设函数预测y等于0的区域
I want to give
我想给这条线一个名字
this line, this magenta line that I drew a name.
就是我刚刚画的这条洋红色线
This line there is called
这条线被称为
the decision boundary.
决策边界（decision boundary）
And concretely, this straight line
具体地说 这条直线
X1 plus X equals 3.
满足x1+x2=3
That corresponds to the set of points.
它对应一系列的点
So that corresponds to the region
它对应
where H of X is equal
h(x)等于
to 0.5 exactly and
0.5的区域
the decision boundary, that is
决策边界 也就是
this straight line, that's the
这条直线
line that separates the region
将整个平面分成了两部分
where the hypothesis predicts Y equals
其中一片区域假设函数预测y等于1
one from the region
而另一片区域
where the hypothesis predicts that Y is equal to 0.
假设函数预测y等于0
And just to be clear.
我想澄清一下
The decision boundary is a
决策边界是
property of the hypothesis
假设函数的一个属性
including the parameters theta 0, theta 1, theta 2.
它包括参数θ0 θ1 θ2
And in the figure I drew a training set.
在这幅图中 我画了一个训练集
I drew a data set in order to help the visualization.
我画了一组数据 让它更加可视化
But even if we take
但是 即使我们
away the data set, you know
去掉这个数据集
decision boundary and a
这条决策边界
region where we predict Y
和我们预测y等于1
equals 1 versus Y equals zero.
与y等于0的区域
That's a property of the
它们都是
hypothesis and of the
假设函数的属性
parameters of the hypothesis, and
决定于其参数
not a property of the data set.
它不是数据集的属性
Later on, of course, we'll talk
当然 我们后面还将讨论
about how to fit the
如何拟合参数
parameters and there we'll
那时 我们将
end up using the training set,
使用训练集
or using our data, to determine the value of the parameters.
使用我们的数据 来确定参数的取值
But once we have particular values
但是 一旦我们有确定的参数取值
for the parameters: theta 0, theta 1, theta 2.
有确定的θ0 θ1 θ2
Then that completely defines
我们就将完全确定
the decision boundary and we
决策边界
don't actually need to plot
这时 我们实际上并不需要
a training set in order
在绘制决策边界的时候
to plot the decision boundary.
绘制训练集
Let's now look at a more
现在 让我们看一个
complex example where, as
更复杂的例子
usual, I have crosses to
和往常一样 我使用十字 (X)
denote my positive examples and
表示我的正样本
O's to denote my negative examples.
圆圈 (O) 的表示我的负样本
Given a training set like this,
给定这样的一个训练集
how can I get logistic regression
我怎样才能使用逻辑回归
to fit this sort of data?
拟合这些数据呢？
Earlier, when we were talking about
早些时候 当我们谈论
polynomial regression or when
多项式回归
we're linear regression, we talked
或线性回归时
about how we can add extra
我们谈到可以添加额外的
higher order polynomial terms to the features.
高阶多项式项
And we can do the same for logistic regression.
同样我们也可以对逻辑回归使用相同的方法
Concretely, let's say my hypothesis looks like this.
具体地说 假如我的假设函数是这样的
Where I've added two extra
我已经添加了两个额外的特征
features, X1 squared and X2 squared, to my features.
x1平方和x2平方
So that I now have 5 parameters,
所以 我现在有5个参数
theta 0 through theta 4.
θ0 到 θ4
As before, we'll defer to
之前讲过 我们会
the next video our discussion
在下一个视频中讨论
on how to automatically choose
如何自动选择
values for the parameters theta 0 through theta 4.
参数θ0到θ4的取值
But let's say that
但是 假设我
very procedure to be specified,
已经使用了这个方法
I end up choosing theta 0
我最终选择θ0等于-1
equals minus 1, theta 1
θ1等于0
equals 0, theta 2
θ2等于0
equals 0, theta 3 equals
θ3等于1
1, and theta 4 equals 1.
θ4等于1
What this means
这意味着
is that with this particular choice
在这个参数选择下
of parameters, my parameter
我的参数向量
vector theta looks like minus 1, 0, 0, 1, 1.
θ将是[-1 0 0 1 1]
Following our earlier discussion, this
根据我们前面的讨论
means that my hypothesis will predict
这意味着我的假设函数将预测
that Y is equal to 1
y=1
whenever minus 1 plus X1
只要-1加x1平方
squared plus X2 squared is greater than or equal to 0.
加x2平方大于等于0
This is whenever theta transpose
也就是θ转置
times my theta transpose
我的θ转置
my features is greater than or equal to 0.
乘以特征变量大于等于0的时候
And if I take minus
如果我将
1 and just bring this to
-1放到不等式右侧
the right, I'm saying that
我可以说
my hypothesis will predict that
我的假设函数将预测
Y is equal to 1
y=1
whenever X1 squared plus
只要x1平方加
X2 squared is greater than or equal to 1.
x2的平方大于等于1
So, what does decision boundary look like?
那么决策边界是什么样子的呢？
Well, if you were to plot the
好吧 如果我们绘制
curve for X1 squared plus
x1平方加
X2 squared equals 1.
x2的平方等于1的曲线
Some of you will
你们有些人已经
that is the equation for
知道这个方程对应
a circle of radius
半径为1
1 centered around the origin.
原点为中心的圆
So, that is my decision boundary.
所以 这就是我们的决策边界
And everything outside the
圆外面的一切
circle I'm going to predict
我将预测
as Y equals 1.
y=1
So out here is, you know, my
所以这里就是
Y equals 1 region.
y等于1的区域
I'm going to predict Y equals 1 out here.
我们在这里预测y=1
And inside the circle is where
而在圆里面
I'll predict Y is equal to 0.
我会预测y=0
So, by adding these more
因此 通过增加这些
complex or these polynomial terms to my features as well.
复杂的多项式特征变量
I can get more complex decision
我可以得到更复杂的决定边界
boundaries that don't just
而不只是
try to separate the positive and negative examples of a straight line.
用直线分开正负样本
I can get in this example
在这个例子中 我可以得到
a decision boundary that's a circle.
一个圆形的决策边界
Once again the decision boundary
再次强调 决策边界
is a property not of
不是训练集的属性
the training set, but of the hypothesis and of the parameters.
而是假设本身及其参数的属性
So long as we've
只要我们
given my parameter vector theta,
给定了参数向量θ
that defines the decision
圆形的决定边界
boundary which is the circle.
就确定了
But the training set is not what we use to define decision boundary.
我们不是用训练集来定义的决策边界
The training set may be used to fit the parameters theta.
我们用训练集来拟合参数θ
We'll talk about how to do that later.
以后我们将谈论如何做到这一点
But once you have the
但是 一旦你有
parameters theta, that is what defines the decision boundary.
参数θ它就确定了决策边界
Let me put back the training set
让我重新显示训练集
just for visualization.
以方便可视化
And finally, let's look at a more complex example.
最后 让我们来看看一个更复杂的例子
So can we come up
我们可以得到
with even more complex decision boundaries and this?
更复杂的决策边界吗？
If I have even higher
如果我有
order polynomial terms, so things
高阶多项式特征变量
like X1 squared, X1
比如x1平方
squared X2, X1 squared
x1平方乘以x2 x1平方乘以x2平方
X2 squared, and so on.
等等
If I have much higher order
如果我有更高阶
polynomials, then it's possible
多项式 那么可以证明
to show that you can get
你将得到
even more complex decision boundaries and
更复杂的决策边界
logistic regression can be
而逻辑回归
used to find the zero boundaries
可以用于找到决策边界
that may, for example, be
例如
an ellipse like that, or
这样一个椭圆
maybe with a different setting of
或者参数不同的椭圆
the parameters, maybe you
也许你
can get instead a different decision boundary that
可以得到一个不同的决定边界
may even look like, you know, some funny
像这个样子
shape like that.
一些有趣的形状
Or for even more complex examples
或者更为复杂的例子
you can also get decision boundaries
你也可以得到决策边界
that can look like, you know,
看起来这样
more complex shapes like that.
这样更复杂的形状
Where everything in here you
在这个区域
predict Y equals 1, and
你预测y=1
everything outside you predict Y equals 0.
在这个区域外面你预测y=0
So these higher order polynomial
因此 这些高阶多项式
features you can get very complex decision boundaries.
特征变量 可以让你得到非常复杂的决策边界
So with these visualizations, I
因此 通过这些可视化图形
hope that gives you a
我希望告诉你
what's the range of hypothesis
什么范围的假设函数
functions we can represent using
我们可以使用
the representation that we have for logistic regression.
逻辑回归来表示
Now that we know what H of X can represent.
现在我们知道了h(x)表示什么
What I'd like to do next in
在下一个视频中
the following video is talk
我将介绍
about how to automatically choose the parameters theta.
如何自动选择参数θ
So that given a training
使我们能在给定一个训练集时
set we can automatically fit the parameters to our data.
我们可以根据数据自动拟合参数